<resources>

    <string name="title_activity_login">Sign in</string>

    <!-- Strings related to login -->
    <string name="prompt_email">Email</string>
    <string name="prompt_password">4-digit passcode</string>  
    <string name="prompt_username">username</string>
    <string name="prompt_name">name</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in_register"><b>Sign in</b> or register</string>
    <string name="action_sign_up_short">Sign Up</string>    
    <string name="action_sign_out_short">Sign Out</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in_short">Sign In</string>
    <string name="action_forgot_password">Recover lost password</string>
    <string name="login_progress_signing_in">Signing In&#8230;</string>
    <string name="sign_progress_signing_up">Signing Up&#8230;</string>
    <string name="error_invalid_email">This email address is invalid</string>
    <string name="error_invalid_password">Only 4-digit numbers can be accepted</string>
    <string name="error_incorrect_password">This password is incorrect</string>
    <string name="error_field_required">This field is required</string>
    <string name="check_list_1">I agree that any nature photos I take using the NatureNet application may be uploaded to the tabletop at ACES
and/or a website now under development.</string>
	<string name="check_list_2">I agree to allow any comments, observations, and profile information that I choose to share with others via the
online application to be visible to others who use the application at the same time or after me.</string>
	<string name="check_list_3">I agree to be videotaped/audiotaped during my participation in this study.</string>
	<string name="check_list_4">I agree to complete a short questionnaire during or after my participation in this study.</string>
	<string name="step1">You are invited to participate in NatureNet, a research project being conducted by the researchers listed on the bottom of the page
[in consultation with Jim Kravitz, Director of Naturalist Programs at ACES]. In order for us to collect and study the way people are 
using technology like NatureNet, we must have your consent. In simplest terms, we hope you will use a mobile device, multi-touch d
isplay, and website to:
\n\n
&#8226; Take pictures and make observations about the natural world\n
&#8226; Share those observations with other visitors\n
&#8226; Share ideas you have about improving the design of our application\n
&#8226; Comment on the observations and ideas of others.\n
\n
The researchers and other visitors will be able to look at your contributions and comments 
via the tabletop or website, and we may ask you if you are willing to answer a few questions 
(either on paper, by phone, or face to face) about your whole experience.  You may stop participating at any time.
\n\n
A longer version of this consent form is available [at the ACES front desk/from Prof Yeh/Maher/Preece] or [nature-net.org], or you can indicate 
your understanding and willingness to participate in our study by checking off the boxes on the next screen.</string>
	<string name="step2">To participate in NatureNet we will need you to agree to a few things:\n</string>
    <string name="step2_q1">(Required) I agree that any nature photos I take using the NatureNet application may be uploaded to the tabletop at ACES and/or a website now under development.</string>
    <string name="step2_q2">(Required) I agree to allow any comments, observations, and profile information that I choose to share with others via the online application to be visible to others who use the application at the same time or after me.</string>
    <string name="step2_q3">(Optional) I agree to be videotaped/audiotaped during my participation in this study.</string>
    <string name="step2_q4">(Optional) I agree to complete a short questionnaire during or after my participation in this study.</string>
  
    <string name="title_activity_consent">Consent</string>
</resources>
